Yeah.
ใช่
No when you look at the capability today i think it's
ตอนที่มองดูความสามารถในวันนี้ ผมคิดว่ามีคำถามสำคัญมากที่ต้องถามว่า
also very important question to say well
แล้วแผนการพัฒนาในอนาคตเป็นอย่างไร
what is the road map you know how much
ระบบพวกนี้จะดีขึ้นแค่ไหน
better are these systems
มันดีขึ้นได้มากแค่ไหน
and how much more complex
และ circuit ที่ซับซ้อนแค่ไหน
are gonna be the circus that we're able to execute
ที่เราจะสามารถรันได้
and for that we have develop a very important metric
สำหรับเรื่องนั้น เราได้พัฒนาตัวชี้วัดที่สำคัญมาก
are called quantum volume
ที่เรียกว่า quantum volume
sometimes you may read or hear in the popular press
บางทีในสื่อทั่วไปอาจจะได้อ่านหรือได้ยิน
the number of cubids and you know
เรื่องจำนวน qubit และ
and and as a measure of progress
ใช้มันเป็นตัววัดความก้าวหน้า
i'll tell you straight that
ขอบอกตรงๆ เลยว่า
just a number of cubits in the machine is not a
แค่จำนวน qubit ในเครื่องไม่ใช่
good measure of progress
ตัววัดความก้าวหน้าที่ดี
progress needs to be measured by
ความก้าวหน้าต้องวัดจาก
the level of complexity of the circuit that you can execute
ระดับความซับซ้อนของ circuit ที่สามารถรันได้
cubits and these good machines are not perfect today
qubit และเครื่องพวกนี้ยังไม่สมบูรณ์แบบในวันนี้
and they have errors i introduce by the coupling of
มันมีข้อผิดพลาดที่เกิดจากการที่ระบบ
the system to the external world
ถูกรบกวนจากโลกภายนอก
the very power of these cubits
พลังอันยิ่งใหญ่ของ qubit เหล่านี้
of entanglement and those properties
ทั้งเรื่อง entanglement และคุณสมบัติต่างๆ
are also make them both powerful
ทำให้มันทั้งทรงพลัง
and delicate to the intersection
และบอบบางต่อการรบกวนจากภายนอก
and connection to the outside world
และการเชื่อมต่อกับโลกภายนอก
so you need to lower the error rate
ดังนั้นต้องลดอัตราข้อผิดพลาด
while you increase the cubit count
ในขณะที่เพิ่มจำนวน qubit ขึ้นด้วย
so that's where it's depicted here
นั่นคือสิ่งที่แสดงในแผนภาพนี้
would you really want to do it you want to move in the diagonal
ถ้าอยากทำให้สำเร็จจริงๆ ต้องเดินในทิศทางแนวทแยง
and quantum volume is a measure that incorporates
และ quantum volume คือตัววัดที่รวม
both of those metrics and some key additional considerations
ทั้งสองตัวชี้วัดนั้น และปัจจัยสำคัญอื่นๆ เข้าไว้ด้วยกัน